Guide to the Marjorie Dodd MacCracken Papers, 1908-1948
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Marjorie Dodd MacCracken Papers
1908-1948
MacCracken, Marjorie Dodd
2.1 cubic feet (7 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Correspondence and other materials pertaining to Marjorie Dodd MacCracken, wife of Henry Noble MacCracken, president of Vassar College 1915-1946. Also includes poems and miscellaneous personal papers.
Biographical Note
Marjorie Dodd MacCracken was born June 12, 1882 to Melvina Eliza and Samuel Calvin Tate Dodd. In 1907, she married Henry Noble MacCracken who was president of Vassar College from 1915-1946. In 1916, MacCracken founded Lincoln Center in Poughkeepsie and served on the Board of Directors. MacCracken was an amateur painter and poet. She died in 1974.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence and other materials pertaining to Marjorie Dodd MacCracken, wife of Henry Noble MacCracken, president of Vassar College 1915-1946. Also includes poems and miscellaneous personal papers.
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Henry Noble MacCracken Papers
Subject Headings
Names:
MacCracken, H. N. (Henry Noble), 1880-1970; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945
Organizations:
Vassar College--Presidents
Subjects:
Women's colleges--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie; College presidents
VCL Categories
Family; Vassar College
Encoding Information
Encoded by Adrienne Turner, October 2008.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the MacCracken family. Helen Kenyon Letters transferred from the Autograph Files, June 2009.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in three series, and chronologically within each of those series.
Series List
- Series I. Correspondence - Henry N. MacCracken
- Series II. Correspondence - Miscellaneous
- Series III. Poems and Miscellaneous
Container List
- Correspondence - Henry N. MacCracken
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 4 Mar. 1908 – 21 Aug. 1908; (18 letters) (Folder 1.1)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 2 July 1909 – 28 Dec. 1909; (5 letters) (Folder 1.2)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 24 June 1910 - 30 June 1910; (7 letters) (Folder 1.3)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 18 Sept. 1911 - 27 Sept. 1911; (4 letters) (Folder 1.4)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 23 July 1912 - 5 Dec. 1912; (12 letters) (Folder 1.5)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 27 Mar. 1913 - 24 Sept. 1913; (7 letters) (Folder 2.1)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 2 Feb. 1914 - 1 Apr. 1914; (12 letters) (Folder 2.2)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 13 Apr. 1915 - 24 Oct. 1915; (14 letters) (Folder 2.3)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 20 Mar. 1916 - 28 Sept. 1916; (14 letters) (Folder 2.4)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 1 June 1917 - 4 Oct. 1917; (24 letters) (Folder 2.5)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 3 Jan. 1918 - 7 Nov. 1918; (18 letters) (Folder 3.1)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 24 June 1919 - 25 Aug. 1919; (16 letters) (Folder 3.2)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 17 June 1920 - 20 July 1920; (22 letters) (Folder 3.3)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 23 July 1920 - 2 Aug. 1920; (8 letters) (Folder 3.4)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 9 Aug. 1920 - 7 Oct. 1920; (5 letters) (Folder 3.5)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 30 Nov. 1920 - 13 Dec. 1920; (14 letters) (Folder 4.1)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 10 July 1921 - 4 Aug. 1921; (16 letters) (Folder 4.2)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 12 Oct. 1921 - 26 Oct. 1921; (13 letters) (Folder 4.3)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 6 Jan. 1923 - 6 July 1923; (23 letters) (Folder 4.5)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 1 Jan. 1924 - 8 Jan.1924; (4 letters) (Folder 4.6)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 17 Feb. 1925 - 20 Aug. 1925; (24 letters) (Folder 4.7)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 27 June 1928 - 28 Nov. 1932; (8 letters, 10 postcards) (Folder 7.1)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 7 Mar. 1933 - 16 Oct. 1933; (9 letters) (Folder 7.2)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 11 Mar. 1934 - 26 Mar. 1934; (14 letters, 1 postcard) (Folder 7.3)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 9 June 1937 - 2 Dec. 1937; (4 letters, 6 postcards) (Folder 7.4)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 9 June 1938 - 11 Mar. 1940; (13 letters, 7 postcards, 1 telegram) (Folder 7.5)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 17 Nov. 1941 - 1945; (12 letters) (Folder 7.6)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, 1947 - 1948; (15 letters) (Folder 7.7)
  - Henry Noble MacCracken, n. d.; (7 letters) (Folder 7.8)
- Series II Correspondence - Miscellaneous
  - Unknown, 5 July 1923 - 6 July 1923; (3 letters) (Folder 5.1)
  - John D. Rockefeller, 30 Sept. 1914 - 26 Mar.1915; (2 letters) (Folder 5.2)
  - Franklin D. Roosevelt, 7 Dec. 1931 - 15 Dec. 1931; (2 letters) (Folder 5.3)
  - Helen Hadley, 6 Feb. 1915 - 15 May 1925; (2 letters) (Folder 5.4)
  - Helen Kenyon, Sep - Nov 1918; (2 letters) (Folder 5.34)
  - G. Johnstin Ross, 27 Apr. 1920; (1 letter) (Folder 5.5)
  - Elizabeth H. Haight, 6 Feb. 1925; (1 letter) (Folder 5.6)
  - Elizabeth Aitken, 6 Mar. 1925; (1 letter) (Folder 5.7)
  - Grace Chester Gow, 13 Apr. 1926; (1 letter) (Folder 5.8)
  - Unknown, 21 Apr. 1927; (1 letter) (Folder 5.9)
  - Frances R. Biggs, 19 Jan. 1929; (1 letter) (Folder 5.10)
  - M. Miller, 10 Apr. 1930; (1 letter) (Folder 5.11)
  - Mrs. J.R. Fisher, 23 Mar. 1931; (1 letter) (Folder 5.12)
  - Margaret Frohnkneiht, 9 Oct. 1931; (1 letter) (Folder 5.13)
  - Myra H. Avery, 7 Mar. 1933; (1 letter) (Folder 5.14)
  - Ellen Bartlett, 22 Apr. 1933; (1 letter) (Folder 5.15)
  - Wm. L. Thacker, 2 June 1933; (1 letter) (Folder 5. 16)
  - Sue Breul, 27 Nov. 1933; (1 letter) (Folder 5. 17)
  - Aunt Ella, 29 Dec. 1933; (3 letters) (Folder 5.18)
  - Libby, 18 Jan. 1935; (1 letter) (Folder 5.19)
  - Natalie Kneeland, 24 Oct. 1935; (1 letter) (Folder 5.20)
  - Margaret Walker, 8 Nov. 1936; (1 letter) (Folder 5.21)
  - Arthur Merry, 18 Dec. 1940; (1 letter) (Folder 5.22)
  - Mana Linderann-Pitlann, 9 Sept. 1941; (1 letter) (Folder 5.23)
  - Ruter Howlett, 18 Oct. 1943; (1 letter) (Folder 5.24)
  - Beatrice, n. d.; (1 letter) (Folder 5.25)
  - Gertrude Buck, n. d.; (1 letter) (Folder 5.26)
  - Clara Glass (1 letter), n. d.; (1 letter) (Folder 5.27)
  - Mildred, 13 Aug. n. y.; (1 letter) (Folder 5.28)
  - Ray Morris, 17 Oct. n. y.; (1 letter) (Folder 5.29)
  - Grace T. Spencer, n. d.; (1 letter) (Folder 5.30)
  - Helen Spencer, 6 Feb. n. y.; (1 letter) (Folder 5.31)
  - Anne Stommel, 21 Jan. n. y.; (1 letter) (Folder 5.32)
  - Marion W. Taylor, 12 Jun. n. y.; (1 letter) (Folder 5.33)
- Series III Poems and Miscellaneous
  - Poems, unknown, 1908 - [1925]; (14 pages) (Folder 6.1)
  - John H. Flagg, 12 June 1902; (1 page) (Folder 6.2)
  - Florence M. Flagg, n. d.; (2 pages) (Folder 6.3)
  - Maisry MacCracken, n. d.; (2 pages) (Folder 6.4)
  - Cards, [1933]; (4 cards) (Folder 6.5)
  - Blank postcards, 1908 - [1925]; (31 postcards) (Folder 6.6)
  - Williams-Porter Hospital, 1 Jan. 1930; (1 page) (Folder 6.7)
  - Article; M. MacCracken, June 1938; (1 page) (Folder 6.8)
  - Painting; M. MacCracken, 3 Jun. 1934; (1 photo) (Folder 6.9)
  - Junior Red Cross speech, Nov. 1933?; (1 page) (Folder 6.10)
  - Sheet of Music, n. d.; (1 sheet) (Folder 6.11)
  - Receipts from purchases made during trip to Europe including two Rembrandts, 2 Oct. 1922 - 16 Oct. 1922; (1 letters, 4 receipts) (Folder 4.4)
  - Key labeled "Mr. Dodd’s Trunk" (Box 6)